Gentle I.

About

Intro Hey there! My name is Ilya Menshikov, I'm developer and researcher.

For the last 6 years I have been working as web developer on Ruby. The largest project I worked at was PULSCEN.RU.

Recently, I have been also doing research in the field of computational linguistics. The topics of my research were sentiment analysis and approaches to automated thesauri construction.

Goals To grow up to top developer

Hobby I love music, programming, science and coffee. I'm playing in the board games and doing magic.

Education

- 2015— **PhD, 09.06.01**, Institute of Fundamental Education, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia.
- 2013—2015 Master of Information Systems, Institute of Fundamental Education, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia.
- 2009—2013 Bachelor of Information Systems, Institute of Physics and Technology, Ural Federal University, Yekaterinburg, Russia.

Work Experience

2016— **Developer**, SKB-Kontur.

- Backend developmet on Ruby language;
- Frontend development;
- Development of a document management system for Decathlon company
- Development of bank guarantees issuance portal;

2014—2016 **Developer**, Under NDA.

- Backend development on Ruby language;
- Infrastructure automation and maintenance;
- Frontend development;
- Partially project management;

2011—2014 **Developer**, Software Development Department, ABAK–PRESS Publising House, Yekaterinburg, Russia.

- Development of the PULSCEN.ru website using Ruby on Rails;
- Development of the DKVARTAL.ru website using Ruby on Rails;
- Initiation of the Functional and Unit Testing of the DKVARTAL.ru;
- Creating a wiki-system and nlp algorythms at the DKVARTAL.ru.
- Creating some libraries on ruby language (Sitemap, EasyMailChimp)

2011—2011 Developer, Elitmaster, Yekaterinburg, Russia.

- Development of the Yii-based CMS;
- o Development of the corporate system for 1litr;
- Development and support of a big variety of PHP web-sytes.

Languages

Russian Na

Native

English Intermediate

Skills

Programming languages

Ruby Ruby on Rails, Sinatra JavaScript JQuery

 ${\it Had some \quad Go, Java, Python, C\#}$

expirience

DB

RDBMS PostgreSQL NoSQL Redis

Other

Search Systems Elasticsearch SCM Git

Social and Professional Networks

 $Git Hub \quad github.com/unkmas$

VK vk.com/unkmas

Selected Awards and Achievements

- 2013 Winner of "The participant of the youth scientific innovation contest" grant contest.
- 2012 Winner of "SKB Kontur grant competition".
- 2010 Participant of the ACM International Collegiate Programming Contest.
- 2009 Prizewinner of the USTU-UPI Research Exhibition.
- 2009 Silver Certificate of the USTU-UPI Rector.
- 2009 Gold Certificate of the USTU-UPI Rector.